Robert Garrett Collection of Ethiopic Magic Scrolls, 1700-1900: Finding Aid C0744.04
Manuscripts Division
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 116, 1870-1899; 116; 3 pieces of parchment sewn together. 1 col., written in black with rubrics (in purple ink) in a moderate hand (5mm), a different smaller hand (3mm) at the end of the scroll, framed within an uncolored linear border. 3 talismanic drawings. (Box 3)
  Central lozenge with transverse cross formed of lobed arms ending in florettes, set against a ground of concentric circles. (In ink with purple color.)
  Equestrian figure spearing a naked prostrate figure beneath his horse. (St. Susenyos slaying the demon Werzelya.) (In ink with purple color.)
  Hand cross with sun and moon. (In ink with purple color.)
  Owner: Amätä S'eyon (f.)
  - Prayer and Legend of Susenyos, late 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer for Blood Clotting and against Hemorrhage, late 19th century; 1 item
    Contains reference to the Doctrina Arcanorum [temhertä hebu'at].
  - Prayer for Binding Demons, Barya and Légéwon, late 19th century; 1 item
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 117, 1730-1770; 117; 2 pieces of parchment sewn together. 1 col., written in black with rubrics in an angular and somewhat uneven hand (4-5mm). 3 talismanic drawings. Preserved in a leather cylinder pouch (2 pieces). NB Unusually, the scroll contains an indication of dating in the mention of "our Bishop Abba Qérlos and our King Iyo'as" towards the end of prayer no. 1; Iyo'as I (r. 1755-69.) (Box 3)
  Eight-pointed star design, without a central face, constructed within a grid of 9 squares, with abstract decorative infill. (In ink with red and yellow color, now slightly faded.)
  Human figure, the body reduced to a geometric pattern, set against a ground of squares. (In ink with red and yellow color, now slightly faded.)
  Grid of 9 squares with various infill designs: transverse crosses, sun, moon and dots. (In ink with red and yellow color, now slightly faded.)
  Owner: the original owner's name, Wäldä Mika'él (m.), has been partly replaced by that of Wälättä Egzér (f.)
  - The Text Known as the Net of Solomon [Märbäbtä Sälomon] for Ensnaring Demons, mid 18th century; 1 item
    part only
  - Prayer against Spells Classified According to the Method of Casting the Spell and the Regional Origin of the Caster. 3, mid 18th century; 1 item
  - Prayer for Undoing Spells, mid 18th century; 1 item
    Untitled. Contains the opening of the Gospel of John.
  - Prayer against Foul Légéwon "Who Cuts the Hearts of Men"; Prayer against Colic, mid 18th century; 1 item
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 118, 1850-1899; 118; 3 pieces of parchment sewn together. 1 col., written in black with rubrics in a moderate hand (5-6mm), framed within a zigzag border in black. 2 talismanic drawings. (Box 3)
  Grid of 15 squares with identical transverse cross infill designs. (In black and red ink.)
  Grid of 9 squares with alternate transverse cross and face (some inverted) infill designs. (In black and red ink.)
  Owner: Wälättä Gäbre'él [Mässäläch] (f.)
  - Prayer against Sickness Caused by Barya and Légéwon, Headache, Colic, (Chest) Pain and Rheumatism, Mäggañña, Gusemt, Typhoid, Fever and Shotälay, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
  - Prayer against the Evil Eye and S'ela Wägi, Followed by the Prayer and Legend of Susenyos, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
  - Prayer against Hemorrhage, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
  - Prayer against Nädra [sic], circa 1850-1899; 1 item
    Contains the story of the witch encountered by Jesus and the disciples by the Sea of Galilee.
  - Prayer for Expelling Demons, Consisting of a Sälam (Hymn of Salutation) to Phanuel, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 119, 1770-1830; 119; 2 pieces of parchment sewn together. 1 col., written in black with rubrics in a generally well-formed hand (4-5mm). 4 talismanic drawings. (Box 3)
  Eight-pointed star design with central face constructed in a grid of 9 squares. (In ink with reddish brown and yellow color.)
  Face framed by four serpent arms. (In ink with reddish brown and yellow color.)
  Face at the center of a cruciform design with four lobed extensions containing eye-motifs, (In ink with reddish brown and yellow color.)
  Eight-pointed star design with central face. (In ink with reddish brown and yellow color.)
  Owner: the original owner's name, partially still legible as Mä— Kidan (f.), has been overwritten by that of Wälättä Täklä Haymanot (f.)
  - Prayer against the Evil Eye, Barya and Légéwon, Algum and Däsk; Prayers against Various Diseases, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
    Contains the secret names of Solomon [asmatä Sälomon] or Net of Solomon.
  - Prayer for Blood Clotting (Arge'a Däm) and against Hemorrhage and Miscarriage, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
  - Prayer against Colic, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 120, 1850-1899; 120; 2 pieces of parchment sewn together. 1 col., written in black with rubrics (both now somewhat rubbed) in a mediocre hand (3-4mm ), framed within a linear border colored yellow. 2 talismanic drawings. Preserved within a leather cylinder pouch, only one half now remaining. (Box 3)
  Guardian angel with drawn sword. (in ink with yellow color.)
  Guardian angel (?), with four "sun" figures either side. (In ink with yellow and red wash.)
  There is a rough sketch of a hand cross (in ink) at the bottom of the scroll.
  Owner: Habtä Sellasé (m.); a later name, Bizan[ä] Wäld (m.) has been added in many places.
  - Prayer against the Evil Eye of Barya, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
  - Prayer against the Evil Eye of Barya, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
  - Prayer against the Evil Eye of Barya; Prayer against Barya, Légéwon, Algum, Däsk .... etc, as Well as Various Ailments and Shotälay and Werzelya; Prayer for Undoing Spells, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
    In continuo. The beginning of the last prayer is barely legible.
  - The Arabic Formula Bismillahi Rahim, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
    In Ethiopic script.
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 121, circa 1750-1799; 121; 1 box A single piece of vellum, forming the top part of a scroll, the other piece(s) now missing. 1 col., written in black with rubrics in a reasonable hand (4mm), framed within a linear border with traces of red color. 2 talismanic drawings. 795 x 130mm (Box 3)
  Prayer and Legend of Susenyos.
  An intricate derivative of the eight-pointed star design with a central face (a cherub ?), with interlocking arms. (In ink with red, yellow and green color.)
  Another eight-pointed star design with a central face, with heads projecting from between the arms of the central cruciform pattern. (In ink with red, yellow and green color.)
  Owner: Wälättä Maryam (f.); the name Wälättä Sellasé has been inserted later.(f.)
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 122, 1800-1830; 122; 4 pieces of parchment sewn together; there is an extensive repair to one piece. 1 col., written in black in a thick but moderate hand (4mm), framed within a zigzag border in black, now much faded. 3 talismanic drawings. (Box 3)
  Grid of 9 squares with diaper pattern. (In ink with red and yellow color, now faded.)
  Eight-pointed star design with central face. (In ink with pale red and yellow wash.)
  Owner: the original owner's name, Amätä Iyäsus (f.), has been overwritten with that of Wälättä Täklä Haymanot (f.)
  - Prayer for Binding Demons "As in a Fishing Net", early 19th century; 1 item
    The text known as The Net of Solomon (though not called so here). Contains sections against various diseases.
  - The Prayer Known as the Rampart of the Cross [Has'urä Mäsqäl], early 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer and Legend of Susenyos, early 19th century; 1 item
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 123, 1700-1799; 123; 4 pieces of parchment sewn together. 1 col., written in black with rubrics in a clear and somewhat angular hand (4-5mm), framed within a linear border with a small amount of latticework decoration at the top of the scroll. 3 drawings. (Box 3)
  2 hand crosses enclosed within a latticework frame, and separated by a simple vertical line. (In ink with red and yellow color, now faded.)
  2 further hand crosses separated by a simple vertical line. (In ink with red and yellow color, now faded.)
  2 further hand crosses separated by a simple vertical line. (In ink with red color, now faded.)
  Owner: Hadära Mika'él (m.)
  - The Text Known as the Lefafä S'edq or Bandlet of Righteousness, 18th century; 1 item
  - Prayer against the Agony of Death, 18th century; 1 item
    Usually forms part of the latter,
  - Annex to the Lefafä S'edq, Beginning "I Tell You, My Brothers, That You Should Know These Words [of] the Bandlet of Righteousness Which God the Father Gave to Our Lady Mary ..", 18th century; 1 item
  - The Prayer of the Road to Heaven [S'älotä Mängädä Sämay], 18th century; 1 item
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 124, 1770-1830; 124; 3 pieces of parchment sewn together. 1 col., written in black with rubrics in an uneven hand (4-5mm), framed within a linear border colored yellow. No drawings aside from a decorative band at the top of the scroll, and two more within the text. (Box 3)
  Owner: Gäbrä Mika'él [Abushu ?] (m.)
  - Prayer for Anathematizing Satan by the Names of the Trinity, the "15 Prophets, the 12 Apostles, the 12 Disciples, the 500 Companions [bis'], the 318 Orthodox ... of Nicea, the 4 Evangelists ...." etc, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
    Opening illegible.
  - Prayer for Frightening and Binding Demons "Spoken by Alexander the King on Friday Before Gog and Magog", circa 1770-1830; 1 item
  - Prayer against the Evil Eye, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
  - Sälam (Hymn of Salutation) to Phanuel, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
  - Prayer against the Evil Eye, Zar and Barya, Aynä S'ela and Gusemt, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 125, 1850-1899; 125; Tapering. 3 pieces of parchment sewn together. I col., written in black with rubrics in a thick, mediocre hand (3-5mm), framed between a linear border colored yellow. 3 talismanic drawings. (Box 3)
  Cross composed of a central square and four faces forming the arms, set against a ground decorated with lines and dots. (In ink with reddish brown, blue and yellow color.)
  Abstract design comprising a central vertical with two looped ends, set against a ground of roughly triangular shapes and circles. (In ink with reddish brown, blue and yellow color.) Written across the drawing is, 'save thy maidservant [Wä]lättä Mika'él.'
  Eight-pointed star design without a central face, or a rosette design. (In ink with reddish brown, blue and yellow color.)
  Owner: the original owner's name, ending in [Ma]ryam, has been erased and replaced with that of Wälättä Mika'él (f.)
  - Prayer for Binding Demons (Ma'esäromu Lä'aganent); Prayer against Sickness Caused by Barya, Légéwon, Däsk and Gudalé, as Well as Colic, Headache, Chest Pain and Met'at, etc, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
  - Prayer against Evil Spirits and Demons, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
  - Prayer against Barya, etc, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
  - Prayer against Nädära, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
    Contains the story of Jesus and the Disciples' encounter with a witch by the Sea of Galilee.
  - Sälam (Hymn of Salutation) to Phanuel, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
  - Prayer against (Chest) Pain and Rheumatism, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 126, 1770-1830; 126; 3 pieces of parchment sewn together; a modern piece of twine at the top for tying.. 1 col., written in black with rubrics in a good but somewhat angular hand (4mm), framed within a linear border with a zigzag design. 4 talismanic drawings. Scroll no. 127 is evidently by the same scribe. (Box 3)
  Grid of 9 squares with a face at the center and transverse cross designs in four squares forming an overall cross shape and lobes in the four corner squares. In ink with reddish brown and ochre color.)
  Cross with additional transverse arms. (In ink with red and ochre color.)
  Cross with looped or lobed arms. (In ink with and ochre color.)
  A radiant "sun face". (In ink with reddish brown and yellow color.)
  Owners: Wäldä Abbiyä Egzi' (m.) and Wälättä Abbiyä Egzi' (f.); also Gäbrä Giyorgis (m.), if this is not a later addition.
  - Prayer for Binding the Demon "Who Sees With Eyes of Fire" as God Bound Beryal [Belial] "With 5,000,000 Chains of Fire", circa 1770-1830; 1 item
  - Prayer against Satan, Barya, Lägéwon [sic], Nägärgar, etc, as Well as Various Ailments and Other Malevolent Forces, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
  - Prayer against (Chest) Pain, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
  - Prayer against Colic, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
  - Prayer against the Foul Demon (?) "That Cuts the Hearts of Men", circa 1770-1830; 1 item
    Text illegible.
  - Prayer against Evil Spirits, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
  - Prayer against Evil Spirits, Barya, Däsk, Lägéwon [sic], Mäggañña, Gwesemt, Gudalé, T'äfänt, the Evil Eye, ... etc, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
  - Prayer for Abjuring Satan, the Demons of the Air, the "King of Nuba," the Demons of the Sea, the "King of Afgam," the Demons of the Trees, the "King of Sidaf," etc, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
  - Prayer against Colic, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 127, 1770-1830; 127; 3 pieces of parchment sewn together, with a repair to holes in the skin before writing. 1 col., written in black with rubrics in a good but somewhat angular hand (4mm), framed within a linear border with a zigzag design. 3 talismanic drawings. By the same scribe as scroll. no. 126. (Box 3)
  Grid of 9 squares with a face at the center and transverse cross designs in four squares forming an overall cross shape and pairs of smaller squares in the four corner squares (forming an H-pattern). In ink with reddish brown and ochre color.)
  Owner: Täsfa Sellasé (m.)
  - Prayer for Trapping Demons, the Secret Names of Solomon [Asmatä Sälomon] or the Net of Solomon, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
  - Prayer for Undoing Spells, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
    Here employing both usual titles, mäftehé seray fethatä seray. Classified according to the nationality of the spell caster.
  - Prayer against Satan, Barya, Lägéwon [sic], Nägärgar, Colic and Headache, etc, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
  - Prayer against (Chest) Pain, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
  - Prayer against Colic, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
  - Prayer against Evil Spirits. 7, circa 1770-1830; 1 item
  - Prayer against Foul Lägéwon 'That Cuts the Hearts of Men", circa 1770-1830; 1 item
    Contains extracts from the psalms as well as the gospels.
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 128, 1800-1830; 128; 3 pieces of parchment sewn together. 1 col., written in black with rubrics in a moderate hand (4-5mm), framed within a linear border colored yellow. 3 talismanic drawings. (Box 3)
  Guardian figure (?) with an ornamented cross on the left and a smaller cross and latticework knot on the right. (In ink with red-brown and yellow color.)
  Grid of 9 squares containing transverse crosses composed of eye-motifs. (In ink with red-brown and yellow color.)
  Guardian angel with drawn sword. (In ink with red-brown and yellow color.)
  - Prayer against the Evil Eye, S'elawägi, Barya and Légéwon, early 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer against Barya and Légéwon, Aynä S'ela and Hemorrhage, early 19th century; 1 item
    Contains the legend of Susenyos.
  - Prayer against Barya and Légéwon, Aynä S'ela and Zar "Which Cuts the Hearts of Men", early 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer for Blood Clotting (Märge'é Däm) and against Hemorrhage, early 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer against Barya and Légéwon, Aynä S'ela and Hemorrhage; Prayer against the Evil Eye of "Red and Black People"; Prayers against Colic and (Chest) Pain, early 19th century; 1 item
    In continuo. First prayer contains the prayer known as the rampart of the Cross [has'urä mäsqäl].
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 129, 1870-1899; 129; 3 pieces of parchment sewn together, with a leather thong for tying at the top. 1 col., written in black with rubrics in a large, moderate hand (5-6mm), framed within a linear border colored yellow. 3 talismanic drawings. (Box 3)
  Guardian angel with drawn sword. (In ink with red, pale yellow and blue color.)
  Another guardian angel with drawn sword. (In ink with, pale yellow and blue color.)
  Cross with accompanying sun and moon. (In ink with red, pale yellow and blue color.)
  Owner: Wälättä Heywät Dästa (f.)
  - Prayer against Sickness Caused by "Demons of the Air, the Heavens, the Sea, the Cliff Face, the Dry Land, the Lowlands and the Highlands, the Refuse Tip and the House", late 19th century; 1 item
    Also contains a prayer against sickness caused by barya, légéwon, zar and tegrida, etc.,
  - Prayer against Foul Légéwon "That Cuts the Hearts of Men", late 19th century; 1 item
    Contains a prayer for exorcizing evil spirits by the names of the five nails of the Cross.
  - Prayer against Foul Demons and Sorcerers, late 19th century; 1 item
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 130, 1830-1870; 130; 3 pieces of parchment sewn together; there is some rodent damage to the edges of the scroll. 1 col., written in black with rubrics in a moderate hand (2-4mm). 3 talismanic drawings. (Box 3)
  Guardian angel with drawn sword. (In ink with yellow and possible traces of red color.)
  Eight-pointed star design with central face. (In ink with yellow color.)
  4 seraphim forming a circle. (In ink with some yellow color.)
  Owner: Kinä Sellasé (m.) The name Wälättä Mädhen (f.) has been added later to one of the drawings.
  - Prayer against Sickness Caused by the Evil Eye of Barya, Teal Wägi and the Black Demon (T'eqwer Ganén), Légéwon, Typhoid, Fever, Mari ... etc, mid 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer against Sickness Caused by the Evil Eye of Barya and Ejjä Säbe' (Craftsmen ?), Fälasha and Magicians, Zar and Tegrida ... etc, mid 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer against the Evil Eye, mid 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer against (Chest) Pain, mid 19th century; 1 item
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 131, 1830-1870; 131; 3 pieces of parchment sewn together. 1 col., written in black with rubrics in a good hand (3-4mm), framed within a plain border colored yellow. 4 talismanic drawings. (Box 4)
  Stylized figure between two ornamented crosses, and a bodiless head to the right, with a chevron or zigzag border above and below. (In ink with faded red, blue and yellow color.)
  A series of decorated bands (zigzags, stripes, plain) one containing two faces. (In ink with faded red, blue and yellow color.)
  Eight-pointed star with central face between bands with zigzag decoration. (In ink with faded red, yellow and pale blue color.)
  Two heads set against a background of chevrons or stylized hills surmounted by circle motifs. (In ink with faded red, yellow and pale blue color.)
  Owners: Wälättä Heywät (f.) and once Täsfa Maryam (m.)
  - Prayers against the Evil Eye and Sorcerers ([t'ä]bib ?), Buda and Fälasha, Däsk, Gudali, S'ela Wägi and Other Demonic Forces. The Prayer Known as the Net of Solomon, mid 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer against Shin Bones (Aqweyas'yat [sic]) With Spells Inscribed on Them, mid 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer for the Undoing of Spells (Mäftehé Seray), mid 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer for the Binding of Demons (Ma'esärä Aganent), mid 19th century; 1 item
    Contains the Lord's Prayer.
  - Prayer and Legend of Susenyos, mid 19th century; 1 item
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 132, 1830-1870; 132; 2 pieces of parchment sewn together. 2 cols., written in black with rubrics in a moderate hand (4-5mm), divided by a border decorated with stylized eye motifs with some yellow color. 3 talismanic drawings. (Box 4)
  Grid pattern with alternate transverse cross and stylized eye motif designs. (In ink with some yellow color.)
  Eight-pointed star motif with central face and sylized eye desins in the middle, other spaces filled alternately with stylized angels and lattice-work and eye designs. (In ink with pale red and yellow color.)
  Eight-pointed star with central face and eye motifs. (In ink with yellow and some faded red color.) The owner's name, Gäbrä Iyäsus (m.) is written in the top right-hand corner.
  Owners: Gäbrä Iyäsus (m.) and Wälättä Giyorgis (f.), and occasionally Wälättä Heywät (f.) inserted over erasures.
  - The Prayer Known as the Net of Solomon, mid 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer Entitled the Prayer of Melchizedek Invoking the Archangels Michael, Gabriel, Surafél and Kirubél; Prayers for Salvation Invoking Various Saints and Prophets, mid 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer against Blacksmiths, Gudalé, Däsk, etc, mid 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer against Colic or Stomach Ache, "Coming from the Land of Constantinople", mid 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer against Colic or Stomach Ache, mid 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer against Evil Légéwon "Who Cuts the Hearts of [Men]", mid 19th century; 1 item
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 133, circa 1850-1899; 133; 1 box 2 pieces of parchment sewn together. 1 col., written in black with rubrics in a neat but angular hand (3-4mm). 2 talismanic drawings. 1380 x 60mm (Box 4)
  The text known as the Bandlet of Righteousness (Lefafä S'edq); account of the sufferings of Our Lord. Includes several prayers titled the prayer of the way to Heaven.
  Rough drawing of crosses. (In ink with some red color.) Rough drawing of a cross. (In ink with some red color.)
  Owners: no owner's name is evident.
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 134, 1850-1899; 134; 2 pieces of parchment sewn together. 1 col., written in black with rubrics in an untidy hand (2-5mm). 2 talismanic drawings. (Box 4)
  Stylized crucifixion scene: four figures (below, representing Mary and John (?) and above, Longinus and another soldier (?)) either side of a stylized cross with a central face, and above two angels and three heads. (In ink with faded yellow and red color.)
  Guardian angel with two smaller figures below. The text (in Amharic) reads, "Behold the guardian angel Rufa'él of the excellent horseman Kasa [and] of [his] excellent shield bearer." (In ink with faded yellow and red color.)
  Owner: the name Wäldä Mika'él (m.) has been inserted over erasures; the original owner's name, Kidanä Maryam (m.) appears at the bottom of the scroll.
  - Prayer for the Undoing of Spells (Mäftehé Seray) Ascribed to Cyprianus, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
  - Further Prayers for the Undoing of Spells, "Of Hamasén, Delanta, Wadla, Säqält, Shäwa ..." and Other Regions, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
  - Prayer of the Serpent (S'älot Zä'arwé Medr), circa 1850-1899; 1 item
  - Prayer for Banishing Demons by Invoking the Secret Names of Solomon, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
  - Prayer against Aqweyas'at (Shin Bones ?), Colic or Stomach Ache, Headache and Rheumatism, circa 1850-1899; 1 item
- Garrett Ethiopic Magic Scroll No. 135, 1830-1870; 135; 3 pieces of parchment sewn together. 1 col., written in black with rubrics in a cramped, uneven hand (2-3mm). 4 talismanic drawings. (Box 4)
  Eight-pointed star with central face and four further faces in the quadrants, between bands with protective eye-motif and cross designs. (In ink with red and yellow color.)
  Grid or stylized eight-pointed star design with faces in the center and the quadrants. (In ink with red and yellow color.)
  Cross. (In ink with red and yellow color.)
  Owner: the name Gäbrä Mädhen (m.) has been inserted over erasures.
  - Prayer Invoking the Names of God; Opening of the Gospel of John; Prayers for Protection from Demons Invoking the Archangel Phanuel, mid 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer for the Undoing of Charms (Mäftehé Seray) Invoking the Secret Names of Solomon, mid 19th century; 1 item
  - Prayer against Légéwon 'Who Cuts the Hearts of Men." Account of the Woman With an Issue of Blood from the Gospel of Mark. Prayers against Demons Invoking the Cross, and Calling Upon Mary, mid 19th century; 1 item